Here are a few tips to try if an app or game download seems unusually slow.
First, check your download speed to see what it actually is.
Start a download so you have full bandwidth usage, and then
go to Settings . . . Network settings . . . Bandwidth usage.
Look at Current usage. This shows your network speed.
If it seems lower than you expect, try doing a full reboot of your console.
The reboot closes open games and apps in the background
and starts a new connection to the network.
Your download in progress is suspended during the reboot,
and then resumes where it left off.
Check that the installation is continuing by
going to My games and apps . . . and checking the Queue.
When it shows Installing…, check your network bandwidth usage
to see if it’s gone up. If not, try canceling the download completely and starting again.
It’s possible a corrupted file was interfering with the download.
Canceling removes the corrupted file.
Highlight the game or app . . . press the Menu button on your controller . . .
and choose Cancel.
Then start the installation again.
For more details and troubleshooting options to try,
go to support.xbox.com.
Discover more! Get information and tips from Xbox Help.